let quiz = [
    {
        question:
            'Which is the most important but generally not used criteria for the identification of the species ?',
        options: [
            'Interbreeding ',
            'Morphology',
            'Genetic material ',
            'None of these',
        ],
        answer: 1,
    },
    {
        question:
            'The living organisms can be unexceptionally distinguished from the non-living things on the basis of their ability for',
        options: [
            'interaction with the environment and progressive evolution',
            'reproduction',
            'growth and movement',
            'responsiveness to touch',
        ],
        answer: 2,
    },
    {
        question: 'iological organisation starts with',
        options: [
            'cellular level',
            'organism level',
            'atomic level',
            'sub-microscopic molecular level',
        ],
        answer: 4,
    },
    {
        question:
            'The growth and reproduction are mutually exclusive events in',
        options: [
            'Plants only',
            'Animals only',
            'Higher animals and plants',
            'Lower organisms',
        ],
        answer: 3,
    },
    {
        question:
            'The sum total of chemical reactions occurring in our body is called',
        options: [
            'Metabolism ',
            'Homeostasis',
            'Irritability ',
            'Catabolism',
        ],
        answer: 1,
    },
    {
        question: 'ark the correct statement',
        options: [
            'Only living organisms grow.',
            'Plants grow only up to a certain age.',
            'The growth in living organisms is from inside.',
            'All of these',
        ],
        answer: 3,
    },
    {
        question:
            'Which of the following biological processes do not operate within the life span of a given organism ?',
        options: [
            'Birth and nutrition',
            'Growth and maturation',
            'Metabolism and excretion',
            'Decomposition and mineralization',
        ],
        answer: 4,
    },
    {
        question:
            'Growth development and functioning of living body is due to -',
        options: [
            'Order ',
            'Homeostasis',
            'Metabolism ',
            'Adaptation',
        ],
        answer: 3,
    },
    {
        question:
            'Which type of organisation is found in only living beings ?',
        options: [
            'Atomic ',
            'Molecular',
            'Mixture ',
            'Sub-cellular',
        ],
        answer: 4,
    },
    {
        question: 'Organisation levels in living beings are -',
        options: [
            'Subcellular – cellular – individual – community – population',
            'Atomic – molecular – subcellular – cellular – tissue – organ – individual',
            'Individual – population – organ system – tissue – cellular – molecular – atomic',
            'Atomic – molecular – tissue – individual – ecosystem – community.',
        ],
        answer: 2,
    },
    {
        question: 'Which of the following statement is false?',
        options: [
            'Properties of cellular organelles are present in the molecular constituents of the organelles.',
            'Interactions among the molecular components of the organelles result into properties of cell organelles.',
            'Biology is the story of life on earth.',
            'Biology is the story of evolution of living organisms on earth.',
        ],
        answer: 1,
    },
    {
        question: 'A plant differs from an animal mainly in :',
        options: [
            'Protoplasm ',
            'Vital activities',
            'Nutrition ',
            'Reproduction',
        ],
        answer: 3,
    },
    {
        question:
            'Artificial system of classification classifies plants on the basis of –',
        options: [
            'One or two characters',
            'Phylogenetic trends',
            'Many naturally existing characters',
            'None of the above',
        ],
        answer: 1,
    },
    {
        question:
            'Group of organisms that closely resemble each other and freely interbreed in nature, constitute a–',
        options: ['Species ', 'Genus', 'Family ', 'Taxon'],
        answer: 1,
    },
    {
        question: 'ICBN was first revised in –',
        options: ['1961 ', '1964', '1975 ', '1753'],
        answer: 3,
    },
    {
        question: 'The term taxon refers to –',
        options: [
            'Name of a species',
            'Name of genus',
            'Name of family',
            'A taxonomic group of any rank',
        ],
        answer: 4,
    },
    {
        question:
            'The herbarium specimen on whose basis a new species is described for the first time is called as –',
        options: [
            'Syntype ',
            'Holotype',
            'Paratype ',
            'Neotype',
        ],
        answer: 2,
    },
    {
        question:
            'The scientific naming of plants began with publication of Linnaeus book –',
        options: [
            'Genera plantarum ',
            'Systema naturae',
            'Species plantarum ',
            'Charaka sanhita',
        ],
        answer: 3,
    },
    {
        question: 'The basic unit of classification is –',
        options: [
            'Genus ',
            'Species',
            'Order ',
            'All of these',
        ],
        answer: 2,
    },
    {
        question:
            'Individuals of same species having non-genetic differences due to environment are called –',
        options: [
            'Biotypes ',
            'Ecotype',
            'Ecophenes ',
            'None of these',
        ],
        answer: 3,
    },
    {
        question:
            'Morphologically similar but reproductively isolated species are called –',
        options: [
            'Neontological species ',
            'Sibling species',
            'Allopatric species ',
            'Morpho-species',
        ],
        answer: 2,
    },
    {
        question: 'Plant nomenclature means :',
        options: [
            'To give names to plants without any rules',
            'Nomenclature of plants under the international rules',
            'Nomenclature of plants in local language',
            'Nomenclature of plants in english language',
        ],
        answer: 2,
    },
    {
        question: 'Taxonomy refers to –',
        options: [
            'Plant classification ',
            'Plant nomenclature',
            'Plant affinity ',
            'All of these',
        ],
        answer: 4,
    },
    {
        question: 'Which of the following is a correct name ?',
        options: [
            'Solanum tuberosum',
            'Solanum Tuberosum',
            'Solanum tuberosum Linn.',
            'All of these',
        ],
        answer: 3,
    },
    {
        question: 'Systematics deals with –',
        options: [
            'Classification ',
            'Nomenclature',
            'Plant description ',
            'Plant exploration',
        ],
        answer: 3,
    },
    {
        question: 'Phylogeny refers to –',
        options: [
            'Natural classification',
            'Evolutionary classification',
            'Evolutionary history',
            'Origin of algae',
        ],
        answer: 3,
    },
    {
        question: 'Static concept of species is given by –',
        options: ['Linnaeus ', 'Bentham', 'Koch ', 'Mayr'],
        answer: 1,
    },
    {
        question: 'In taxonomy the first step is :',
        options: [
            'Identification ',
            'Nomenclature',
            'Classification ',
            'Affinities',
        ],
        answer: 1,
    },
    {
        question: 'The suffix - inae signifies the rank :',
        options: [
            'Tribe ',
            'Sub tribe',
            'Sub order ',
            'Sub family',
        ],
        answer: 2,
    },
    {
        question:
            'Species living in different geographical areas are called –',
        options: [
            'Allochronic ',
            'Allopatric',
            'Sympatric ',
            'Siblings',
        ],
        answer: 2,
    }
];
